bookriot.com 2017-11-19

# Privacy Policy | BOOK RIOT

**Updated:  October 1, 2015**

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is intended to inform you of Riot New Media Group, Inc’s (“Riot New Media Group, Inc,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) policies and practices regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information through our site located at <https://bookriot.com/> and any other sites that links to this Privacy Policy (the “Site”). We define “Personal Information” as information that allows someone to identify you personally or contact you, including for example your name, address, telephone number, and email address.

By registering with us or using our Site, you expressly consent to the collection, use, processing, and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you reside outside the United States, you understand that your Personal Information may be processed in countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing personal information may be less stringent than in your country.

Capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given to them in the [Terms of Use](https://bookriot.com/termsofuse/ "Terms of Use") or Contributor Terms, as applicable.

Personal Information You Provide to Us. When you register for an account on our Site, we collect your name, e-mail address, and e-mail preferences, and password for your account. You may also provide us additional information on an optional basis indicated as such in connection with your account and/or your use of our Site. When you choose to participate in a survey, we may collect your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number, age, gender and/or other requested information. When you give us Feedback, we may collect any information that is contained in your Feedback. When you contact us by sending us an e-mail, fax, or letter, we collect your e-mail address, fax number, or mailing address, and any information contained in the e-mail, fax, or letter you send us.

Personal Information You Provide to Us Using Social Networking Connections. When you register your account with Facebook, Twitter, or other third party social networking services (each, a “Social Networking Site”), we collect basic information about you and your friends that is provided to us by the Social Networking Sites. We combine this information with other personal information we collect from the Service. If you elect to share any information with Social Networking Sites while using our Site, we will share such information with the Social Networking Site and their use of such information will be subject to their own privacy policies and not by this Privacy Policy.

Personal Information Collected via Technology. As you use our Site, some information may also be collected passively, including your Internet protocol address, browser type, the website you visited before browsing our Site, pages you viewed, how long you spent on a page, browser language, and access time.

Cookies. We may automatically collect information using “cookies.” Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. Among other things, cookies help us make our Site and your experience better. We use cookies to see which parts and features of our Site are popular and to count visits to our Site.

Web Beacons. We may log information using digital images called “web beacons” (also called “pixel tags”) on our Site or in our emails. We use web beacons to manage cookies, count visits, and to learn what marketing works and what does not. We also use web beacons to tell if you open or act on our emails.

Analytics. We use Google Analytics and other analytics services to help analyze how users use the Site. These analytics services uses cookies to collect and store information such as how often users visit the Site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from these analytics services only to improve our Site and our services. Please see the following links for more information about Google Analytics: http://www.google.com/privacy.html and https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.  
Personal Information from Other Sources. We may receive Personal Information about you from other sources, including other users. We may associate this information with the other Personal Information we have collected about you.

Use of Information  
We use your Personal Information to respond to requests that you make, to personalize your online experience on our Site, and to provide and improve our Site and its associated features and our services.

We track IP protocol addresses in conjunction with session Cookies to analyze our web page flow and to keep track of your session information and clickstream data. We use persistent Cookies to keep track of your login name and password in connection with your use of, and uploading of Your Content through, our Site and to personalize your online experience on our Site.

We may use your Personal Information to send you electronic newsletters or promotional e-mails, unless you have requested not to receive such promotional communications from us. We may also use your Personal Information to send you communications relating to any of our programs for which you have registered, and you may opt out of these communications if you terminate your account on our Site.

We may also use your Personal Information to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information. We reserve the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information at our discretion. “Anonymous Information” means information that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Information.

Disclosure of Personal Information  
Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not trade, rent, or share your Personal Information with third parties, unless you ask or authorize us to do so.

We may provide your Personal Information to third party service providers who work on behalf of or with us to provide our Site and features thereof. However, these service providers do not have any independent right to share this information (except pursuant to a legal requirement such as a subpoena or warrant).

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your Personal Information with our Affiliates in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

If we or our assets related to this Privacy Policy are acquired by another company, or otherwise in connection with a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or dissolution, that company will receive your Personal Information collected by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We may share your information as required by law, or with law enforcement officers acting under the color of law, or if we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to: (1) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us; or (2) to protect and defend ours, our Affiliates,’ other users,’ or your, rights, property or safety.

Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information  
We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Information. When you receive promotional communications from us or our Site, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further promotional communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the promotional e-mail you receive.

Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you administrative e-mails regarding our Site and programs, including without limitation, for example, account creation confirmation, and notices of material changes to our [Terms of Use](https://bookriot.com/termsofuse/ "Terms of Use"), Contributor Terms, or Privacy Policy.

You may change the email address, password and preferences you submitted related to your account on the Site at any time by editing it in your account page or you may delete your account. You may request deletion or modification of your Personal Information by us, but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request, only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete Personal Information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives.

When you visit our Site, we and others give you the following choices about use of mechanisms for tracking, including tracking of your online activities over time and across different websites and online services by third parties. You may also render some web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can typically remove and reject cookies from our Site with your browser settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it could affect how our Site and Services work for you. While we and others give you the choices described in this Policy, there are many ways Web browser signals and other similar mechanisms can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and we may not be aware of or honor every mechanism.

Regarding Children. We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about users who are under the age of 13.

Third Party Websites, Products, Services, Content, and Links. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to third party websites, products, services, or content or to links provided for the foregoing on our Site. Third party providers of such third party websites, products, services, or content, may collect (via tracking technologies like Cookies or web beacons) and use anonymous information regarding your interaction with the third party website, product, service, or content that they deliver and with which you interact.

Online Advertisements.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use cookies, web beacons, and information (such as IP address, your ISP, and the browser you use to visit our Site) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising relevant to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or web beacons in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp or http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

Security. We make reasonable efforts to protect your Personal information, but no company, including Riot New Media Group, Inc, can fully eliminate security risks connected to handling information on the internet.

Amendment. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy, we will change the “Updated” date above.

Contact Information. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by e-mail at bookriot (at) bookriot (dot) com or by writing to us at Riot New Media Group, Inc, 147 Prince Street, Brooklyn, NY 11201, in each case marking the message “Attention: Privacy Policy.”
